phone: (778) 989-6449 || email: jperlas@my.bcit.ca

### **Profile**

BCIT Computer Information Technology student who takes initiative and has high standards in his own work and in group work. I bring experience in leadership and enthusiastic communication to motivate my peers and create a strong chemistry to produce the best results.

## **Technical Skills**

Coding	Hardware / Software	IT	Database
Python	Windows 7, 8, 10	Networking	MySQL
C#	Windows Server 2019	Laptop Repairs	MongoDB
Bash	Linux	Computer Building	SQLite
HTML / CSS / JavaScript	GitHub / Git	Active Directory	
Node.JS / Angular	Postman	Amazon Web Services	
Java	Figma		

# **Academic Projects**

## Outbreak: Source | | Lead Developer

May 2020

### **BCIT Agile Methodology Course**

- Worked alongside with 6 team members including lower term students
- Developed an API heavy idle-game application using the Agile development process and MEAN stack
- Wrote documents and tutorials for lower term students so they can contribute to the project
- Specialized in backend, database, and core mechanics of the game
- Technologies used: MongoDB, Express.Js, Angular, Node.Js, GitHub
- https://github.com/jperlas2019/Outbreak-Source

## HallPass || Lead Designer

May 2020

#### BCIT UX/UI Design Course

- Worked in a team of 3 to design a universal school mobile application
- Designed a mobile app that would link to the school's online services and display information in a familiar user interface
- Created surveys and developed user personas to appropriately design the app according to their problems
- Reviewed peer work and gave constructive criticism to produce a better end product
- Technologies used: Figma
- https://www.figma.com/proto/RJ5UcWjVAWLi2b6fQDyxfB/User-Flows?node-id=6%3A192&scaling=min-zoom

### Python MP3 Player | Lead Developer

Mar - Apr 2020

#### **BCIT Object-Oriented Programming Course**

- Worked with 2 other members using GitHub
- Programmed a music player using Python object-oriented fundamentals with a database and GUI
- Connected SQLite, VLC, and Tkinter to work together and play mp3 files from user's harddrive
- Wrote unit test code and manual tested using CRUD requests with Postman
- Technologies used: Python, SQLite, VLC, Tkinter, GitHub, Postman, eyeD3 module
- https://github.com/jperlas2019/Python-MP3-Player

phone: (778) 989-6449 || email: jperlas@my.bcit.ca

Router Project Feb - Apr 2020

## **BCIT Networking Course**

- Constructed a router using IPv4 and IPv6 to investigate the foundations of computer networking
- Connected over 4 nodes and 3 routers that includes DHCP, NAT, and packet filtering using nftables to make a network
- Set up a DNS server for the network to translate IP addresses into domain names
- Technologies used: CentOS, Red Hat

# Food Ordering Website Feb - Mar 2020

### **BCIT Web Applications Course**

- Developed a food ordering website using MEAN stack and Bootstrap
- Programmed a login page using browser sessions to integrate user roles such as guest and admin
- Integrated security checks so that guests do not have/see admin pages/privileges
- Established a database to store items, price, and use them to calculate price
- Technologies used: MongoDB, Angular, Node.Js, Express.Js, Bootstrap

# Personal Projects

<u>Combo Swipe</u> May 2020 - Present

#### **Unity Mobile Game**

- Currently developing a single player 2D RPG mobile game using Unity and C#
- Programmed multiple data structures for the core mechanics of the game
- Implemented formulas for health, player stats, attack damage, and probability
- Conducted constant manual testing to decrease the potential of bugs and exploits
- Technologies used: Unity, C#

# Experience

#### Beginner Jazz Band Student Teacher

Holy Cross Regional High School Music Program

Sept 2017 - June 2019

- Taught a beginner jazz band consisting of 16 students from grade 8 10 twice a week
- Spoke and presented to large crowds in multiple events to run (emcee)
- Inspired students to learn more about jazz and be motivated to come to class
- Critically analyzed individual playing and playing as a whole to improve each student and the band

#### Rides Operator Jun 2017 - Sep 2018

#### Pacific National Exhibition (PNE)

- Loaded, unloaded, and maintained a roller coaster for over 100 guests for 5 days a week
- Motivated co-workers over long summer days to bring up enthusiasm
- Showed positive attitude and enthusiasm to bring joy to the guests
- Documented maintenance periods and problems with the train to predict future problems
- · Adapted to changes in environment and various people to ensure the best possible experience for guests

# Education

Computer Information Technology Diploma British Columbia Institute of Technology, GPA 86%

Sept 2019 - Present